[{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"1. Flower petals are thrown to purify the air in a Balinese form of this activity known as pendet. The usage of atabaque (“ah-tuh-BAH-kee”) and agogô (“uh-GO-go”) facilitate a type of this practice whose performance allows individuals to become possessed by orixás (“or-EE-shuhs”) and is central to the Brazilian tradition of Candomblé. The tandava form of this activity is often depicted being performed by Nataraja, a depiction of Shiva as the “Lord of” this activity. In Sufi tradition, the Mevlevi order is best known as a group of dervishes, who perform a ritual form of this practice known as “whirling.” For 10 points, name this activity, one form of which was originally performed to appease the volcano goddess Pele, its hula variety. ","answer":"ANSWER: ritual dance [or word forms; accept sacred dance, worship dance, or religious dance; accept “dance in honor of the gods”; accept bebalihan or wali; prompt on whirling until read] <Religion> 2. “Complex interdependence” was proposed in a book promoting a revised theory of this name by Robert Keohane (“KEE-oh-hahn”) and “soft power” advocate Joseph Nye. This type of person responds to only two or three of six moral foundations according to research by Jonathan Haidt (“height”). Paul Krugman ran a blog and published a 2007 book both named for the “Conscience of a” person with this philosophy. The international relations school of this name has roots in Immanuel Kant’s essay on democratic peace theory. Friedrich Hayek and Adam Smith adhered to a free-market “classical” version of this ideology. For 10 points, name this political ideology often opposed to conservatism. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"3. On average, the strain rate of this substance is proportional to the cube of effective shear stress according to Glen’s law. The color of this substance can be attributed [emphasize] not to Rayleigh (“RAY-lee”) scattering, but rather to an overtone of the stretching mode of its molecules. The high albedo of this substance causes a positive feedback loop when its global surface area decreases. Movement of this substance occurs in basal sliding. Because its density is about 920 kilograms per cubic meter, pieces of this substance float in water. Rising sea levels are attributed to the melting of, for 10 points, what substance that covers much of Earth’s polar regions? ","answer":"ANSWER: sea ice [accept ice sheets or icebergs; prompt on frozen water or solid water or snow; do not accept or prompt on “water”] <Other Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"4. In this century, Friedrich Spee’s (“shpay’s”) Cautio Criminalis condemned massive witch hunts in Würzburg and Bamberg. Jacques Callot’s (“ka-LO’s”) depiction of many men hung from a single tree was inspired by a conflict that occurred in this century. 27 Czech leaders were executed in Prague’s Old Town Square during this century, partially as revenge for an earlier event in which Ferdinand II’s Catholic representatives were hurled out a window. During the Battle of Lützen, the Swedish king Gustavus Adolphus died during a conflict in this century that was ended by the Peace of Westphalia. For 10 points, in which century did the Thirty Years’ War take place? ","answer":"ANSWER: 17th century [or the 1600s] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"2. Because a sculpture by this artist was originally intended for the roof of the Florence Duomo, its head and hands are oversized to be made visible. This man’s unfinished sculptures of Rebellious and Dying Slaves were meant to be placed to the sides of a work that features a horned statue of Moses, the tomb of Julius II. For 10 points, name this Italian sculptor of the Pietà and a marble David and painter of the Sistine Chapel’s ceiling. ","answer":"ANSWER: Michelangelo [or Michelangelo di Lodovico Buonarroti Simoni] <Painting/Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"6. In a story by this author, a “learned man” is executed due to the machinations of his own shadow. In another story by this author, a character is given the chance to gain an immortal soul by doing good deeds for three hundred years. This author wrote a story in which a pretty girl is cursed to dance until she becomes a skeleton after repeatedly wearing red shoes to church. No one is willing to admit that they cannot see the title garments until a child points out that the emperor is naked in this author’s story “The Emperor’s New Clothes.” In a story by this author, the title character visits a sea witch to exchange her voice for a pair of legs. For 10 points, name this Danish author of “The Little Mermaid.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Hans Christian Andersen <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"7. Ambipolar diffusion occurs in these substances. These substances will be constrained by ITER, a device based on an idea proposed by Igor Tamm and Andrei Sakharov. High-intensity X-rays can be generated from these substances in a system called a z-pinch. In these substances, the magnetic field is “frozen in” according to Alfvén’s (“all-VANE’s”) theorem. Various properties of these substances can be measured with a Langmuir (“LANG-myoor”) probe. Magnetohydrodynamics models these substances, which are toroidally confined in tokamaks for fusion. For 10 points, auroras and lightning are examples of what ionized gases considered the “fourth state of matter”? ","answer":"ANSWER: plasmas <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"8. When this thinker died, a piece of paper opening “FIRE. God of Abraham, God of Isaac, God of Jacob” was found sewn to this philosopher’s coat. Early in this thinker’s best-known work, he despairs that “the eternal silence of these infinite spaces alarms me.” This thinker declared that “the heart has its reasons which reason knows not” in a posthumous work written after he defended Port Royal scholar Antoine Arnauld (“ar-NO”) and other Jansenists in the Provincial Letters. He advised taking the sacraments to avoid potential infinite loss in a namesake probabilistic argument in his Pensées (“pon-SAY”). For 10 points, name this French philosopher and mathematician who made a namesake “wager” in favor of belief in God. ","answer":"ANSWER: Blaise Pascal <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"9. A crime figure in this city entrapped a rival by offering to sell him the Sieben Brewery and then having him tour it the day of a police raid. That figure, Dean O’Banion, was murdered in a flower shop in this city after tricking Johnny Torrio. After Torrio retired from crime, he left an organization called this city’s “Outfit” to a protégé who was investigated by a group of Prohibition agents called the Untouchables. Eliot Ness helped bring down that boss of this city, whose associates gunned down seven members of Bugs Moran’s North Side gang in the St. Valentine’s Day Massacre. For 10 points, Al Capone dominated crime in what Midwestern city? ","answer":"ANSWER: Chicago <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"0. The speaker of a poem by this author “saw your horrid scales, / Melusina, shining green in the dawn,” and found “the eyes of a girl / drowned a thousand years ago.” This author imagines a visit to the abandoned town of Galta in a hybrid work about Hanuman contemplating the garden of Ravana. A collection of essays by this author of The Monkey Grammarian includes “The Conquest and Colonialism” and “The Day of the Dead.” The line “willow of crystal, a poplar of water” opens this author’s 584-line poem inspired by the Aztec calendar. For 10 points, name this Mexican author of “Sunstone” and The Labyrinth of Solitude. ","answer":"ANSWER: Octavio Paz [or Octavio Paz Lozano] <World/Other Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"1. This process is facilitated by several proteins with Kringle domains. A hydroquinone compound is produced from an epoxide by VKOR in a pathway that leads to this process. Tenase activates a protein during this process’s namesake cascade. Glycosylation and the cleavage of a zymogen involved in this process produce Christmas factor. Heyde’s (“hide’s”) syndrome is characterized by the degradation of von Willebrand factor, which also aids in this process. In this process, fibrinogen is converted to fibrin by thrombin. Platelets are cells that perform, for 10 points, what process defective in hemophiliacs that stops blood loss? ","answer":"ANSWER: blood clotting [or blood coagulation] <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"2. A film by this director features a hitchhiker named Sara, who is played by the same actress as the protagonist’s childhood love. That film by this director features a dream sequence in which a man sees himself in a coffin. A film by this man features a shot that combines the faces of the two main characters, an actress who has stopped speaking and her nurse. A film by this director of Persona follows Isak Borg and his daughter-in-law Marianne as they travel to Lund. In another film by this director, Max von Sydow (“SEE-doh”) stars as Antonius Block, who challenges Death to a game of chess. For 10 points, name this Swedish director of Wild Strawberries and The Seventh Seal. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ingmar Bergman <Other Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"3. A reconstructed landmark from this city is housed in Berlin’s Pergamon Museum and consists of bull and dragon reliefs on a blue-tiled gate. Sennacherib was murdered by his own sons after he sacked this holy city. A Chaldean (“kal-DEE-in”) leader named Nabopolassar founded an empire centered in this city that collapsed after Nabonidus neglected its patron god in favor of the moon deity Sin. Nebuchadnezzar II ruled from this city, to which he supposedly exiled the Jews during a “captivity” named for this city. A law code established a millennium earlier by a ruler of this city codified principles like “an eye for an eye.” For 10 points, name this ancient Mesopotamian city ruled by Hammurabi. ","answer":"ANSWER: Babylon [accept Babylonian Captivity] <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"4. While in this place, a man is advised to “spare the conquered” and “battle down the proud.” Before traveling to this place, a hero is guided through a boundless forest by two doves. Aeacus (“EE-uh-kuss”) and Rhadamanthys preside in this place’s grove of Avernus. This place is invoked in a ritual called nekyia, while it is visited during katabasis. In this place, true dreams exit through a gate of horn while false dreams exit through a gate of ivory. After arriving in Italy, Aeneas (“uh-NEE-iss”) asks the Cumaean Sibyl to guide him to this place, and she tells him to seek a golden bough. For 10 points, name this place where Aeneas sees Anchises (“ann-KY-seez”), Dido, and other dead spirits. ","answer":"ANSWER: the underworld [or Hades or Pluto or Dis; accept Hell] <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"5. The speaker of a poem by this author asks, “Who are you that mumbles in the dark? / And who are you that draws your veil across the stars?” The speaker claims, “They’ll see how beautiful I am / And be ashamed—” after he is sent “to eat in the kitchen / When company comes” in a poem by this author. This poet wrote “the stars went out and so did the moon” near the end of a poem about a man who “slept like a rock or a man that’s dead.” This poet of “I, Too, Sing America” asked, “Does it stink like rotten meat? / Or crust and sugar over—like a syrupy sweet?” about “a dream deferred.” For 10 points, name this Harlem Renaissance poet of “The Weary Blues.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Langston Hughes [or James Mercer Langston Hughes] <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"6. In January 2019, Chris Christie told Congress to “get the hell out” of this practice in response to a bill that proposed a “clearinghouse” between firms in this practice. That legislation was Orrin Hatch’s last major bill and would have targeted this practice by amending the Federal Wire Act. Integrity fees are a controversial 1% tax on singular actions of this practice. In 2018, the Supreme Court overruled PAPSA in Murphy v. NCAA, stating that prohibitions on this practice violated the 10th Amendment. For 10 points, casinos provide what sort of recently legalized practice, in which money is wagered on activities such as football and baseball? ","answer":"ANSWER: sports betting [accept gambling in place of “betting”; prompt on betting by asking “betting on what activity?”; accept specific answers such as “betting on football” so long as they indicate both betting and a sport] <CE/Geo/Other/Pop Culture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"7. During this event, photographer David Burnett captured an image of the mohawked Frenchman Laurent (“lo-RAWN”) wielding a hammer over his head. To celebrate this event, Leonard Bernstein (“BURN-styne”) conducted Beethoven’s Ninth Symphony, but changed the word “Joy” to “Freedom.” While much of the so-called “canvas” was destroyed, Dmitri Vrubal’s depiction of two male politicians kissing was spared during this event. After this event, many Mauerspecht (“MAO-er-shpekt”), or the “stonepeckers” of its central location, tried to claim souvenirs from its rubble. In a speech, Ronald Reagan asked “Mr. Gorbachev” to perform, for 10 points, what 1989 decommissioning of a certain barricade in a German capital? ","answer":"ANSWER: fall of the Berlin Wall [accept destruction, decommissioning, deactivation, demilitarization, or other synonyms in place of “fall”; accept “Tear down this wall!”; prompt on the reunification of Germany or the unification of East and West Germany; prompt on the Peaceful Revolution; prompt on the fall of the inner German border; prompt on “Open this gate!” by asking “what else did he ask Mr. Gorbachev to do in that speech?”; do not accept or prompt on “unification of Germany”] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"8. This author wrote an autobiographical couplet stating, “No man has tasted differing fortunes more, / And thirteen times I have been rich and poor.” This author compared religious minorities to a cock afraid of being trampled by horses in his satirical pamphlet The Shortest Way with the Dissenters. Doors are marked with variations of the word ABRACADABRA in this author’s novel A Journal of the Plague Year. In a novel by this author, a conwoman is born in Newgate Prison and marries five men, including her half brother. The protagonist of a novel by this author sees the footprint of a cannibal whom he names Friday. For 10 points, name this author of Moll Flanders and Robinson Crusoe. ","answer":"ANSWER: Daniel Defoe [or Daniel Foe] <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"9. Admirers often collected this musician’s unconsumed coffee in glass vials. The central C-B-E motif of a symphonic work by this composer was taken from his earlier cycle Les Quatres Élémens (“lay CAT-ruh ay-lay-MAWN”). All but the fifth piece in a collection by this composer are divided into a slow lassan (“LAW-shawn”) and fast friska (“FREESH-kah”). This inventor of the symphonic poem wrote one inspired by Lamartine’s “Les preludes.” A namesake 1840s “mania” affected fans of this composer, who based one set of nineteen piano pieces on the gypsy music of his native country. For 10 points, name this composer of the Hungarian Rhapsodies. ","answer":"ANSWER: Franz Liszt [or Liszt Ferenc; accept Lisztomania] <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"0. A medical solution to lagophthalmos (“lag-off-THAL-muss”), which is the inability of a person to close their eyes completely, is to implant a small amount of this element into the eyelid. Thiosulfate salts of this element are used to slow the progression of rheumatoid arthritis. The Turkevich method synthesizes nanoparticles of this element, which form a colloid in water. It’s not cesium, but this element’s usual color is explained by a 5d to 6s transition. This element is the most malleable metal, and a foil of it was used by Rutherford to discover the nucleus. For 10 points, name this element whose atomic number is 79 and whose symbol is Au. ","answer":"ANSWER: gold [or Au until read] <Chemistry> Bonuses "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this Bengali Nobel laureate who wrote the poetry collection Gitanjali. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rabindranath Tagore [or Robindronath Thakur] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Prolific Tagore translator Juan Ramón Jiménez (“hee-MEN-ess”) was likely inspired by Tagore to coin a style of poetry described by this adjective. This adjective titles a William S. Burroughs novel partly set in Interzone. ","answer":"ANSWER: naked [accept naked poetry or Naked Lunch; accept desnuda or poesía desnuda] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] When Tagore brought his manuscript of Gitanjali on a visit to England, he briefly lost it in one of these places. An Ezra Pound poem titled for one of these places describes “faces in a crowd” as “petals on a wet, black bough.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the subway [accept synonyms; accept “In a Station of the Metro”; accept the London Tube or London Underground; prompt on train stations or synonyms] <World/Other Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name these skirts that come in Romantic “bell” and Classical “pancake” varieties. Barbara Karinska’s “powder puff” design for one of these skirts was adopted by George Balanchine’s (“BAL-un-cheen’s”) ballet company. ","answer":"ANSWER: tutus "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Taglioni was the first to dance in this manner, which was likely why her tutu for La Sylphide was cut at the ankles. Special namesake shoes are used to dance in this manner, in which the weight is placed on the tips of one’s toes. ","answer":"ANSWER: en pointe (“pwahnt”) [accept pointe shoes; accept pointework] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Isadora Duncan was known as much for dancing in bare feet as for wearing this accessory. Vaslav Nijinsky used one of these clothing items to mime masturbation, causing consternation at the premiere of Afternoon of a Faun. ","answer":"ANSWER: scarf [or neckscarves] <Other Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this 1787 essay published under the name “Publius” that defends the power of the proposed U.S. Constitution to check the danger of factions. ","answer":"ANSWER: Federalist No. 10 [or Federalist Paper No. 10 or “The Utility of the Union as a Safeguard against Domestic Faction and Insurrection”; prompt on Federalist Papers by asking “which one?”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Federalist No. 10 was written by this future president who authored the Federalist Papers with John Jay and Alexander Hamilton. ","answer":"ANSWER: James Madison "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Madison’s claim in Federalist No. 10 that factions most often arise from the “unequal distribution of property” was cited in 1913 by this Columbia historian to support his thesis that the U.S. Constitution was primarily shaped by the founders’ financial interests. ","answer":"ANSWER: Charles Beard <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this theory that describes the geometric arrangement of atoms. It is based on the principle that electrons should be as far away from each other as possible. ","answer":"ANSWER: VSEPR (“vesper”) [or valence shell electron pair repulsion theory] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This force is the weakest intermolecular force and is visualized as two lowercase deltas. This force is stronger between larger molecules. ","answer":"ANSWER: instantaneous dipole–induced dipole force [accept London dispersion forces; prompt on van der Waals forces or dispersion forces; do not accept or prompt on partial answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This type of bond is contrasted with covalent bonds and generally forms between a metal and a nonmetal, such as sodium and chlorine in table salt. ","answer":"ANSWER: ionic bond <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this type of event. The speaker laments “he was my North, my South, my East and West” in a W. H. Auden poem titled for the “blues” of one of these events. ","answer":"ANSWER: funeral [accept “Auden’s Funeral” or “Funeral Blues”] [10] “Funeral Blues” begins with this four-word command. This command is followed by commands to “cut off the telephone, / Prevent the dog from barking with a juicy bone.” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] The speaker of “Funeral Blues” also declares “pack up the moon and dismantle” this object. A Shakespeare sonnet begins, “My mistress’ eyes are nothing like” this object. ","answer":"ANSWER: the sun <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Give this action undertaken by the Fernig sisters and the apocryphal Polly Oliver. On his ship, “Calico” Jack employed a pair of pirates known today for performing this action, which they later revealed to stay their executions. ","answer":"ANSWER: cross-dressing [accept descriptions of dressing like a man; prompt on descriptions such as acting like a different person or acting like someone else; do not accept or prompt on “dressing in drag” or “dressing like a woman”] (La Monja Alférez translates as “The Nun Lieutenant,” and the pirates were Anne Bonny and Mary Read.) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] First mentioned hundreds of years after her supposed reign, this cross-dressing woman is said to be the only female pope. After this woman gave birth during a parade, popes legendarily had to be fondled to ensure the existence of their testicles. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pope Joan [accept Ioannes Anglicus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] She’s no pope, but Joan of Arc was burned at the stake for cross-dressing during this lengthy war broadly fought between England and France during the 14th and 15th centuries. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hundred Years’ War <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name or describe this class of musical professionals that included Nicola Porpora’s students Farinelli and Caffarelli. Most of these men had a range equal to that of a modern mezzo-soprano. ","answer":"ANSWER: castrati [or castrato; accept musico or musici; accept evirato or evirati; accept anything clearly indicating their eunuchism or castrated status] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Farinelli sang for the Opera of the Nobility, which was founded in opposition to this composer’s royally supported company. This German wrote the Messiah while employed in England. ","answer":"ANSWER: George Frideric Handel "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Caffarelli premiered Handel’s “Ombra mai fu,” which is nicknamed for this tempo marking. This slow tempo is faster than grave (“GRAH-vay”) but slower than lento or adagio. ","answer":"ANSWER: largo [accept Handel’s Largo; do not accept “larghetto”] <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name these beings made of animated mud or clay. According to legend, Rabbi Judah Loew ben Bezalel created one of these beings to defend the Jewish ghetto of Prague. ","answer":"ANSWER: golems "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Paracelsus suggested animating one of these beings by incubating human sperm in horse dung. These miniature people were said to serve the alchemist who created them. ","answer":"ANSWER: homunculus (“huh-MUN-kyoo-luss”) [or homonculi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Unlike golems or homunculi, this being made of animated dough [emphasize] does not obey his creator. Instead, this character flees the baker and taunts “you can’t catch me” to everyone he meets until he is eaten by a sly fox. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Gingerbread Man [or the Gingerbread Boy] <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This structure, which contains the pistils, can be monocarpous, apocarpous, of syncarpous. It generally refers to the collective female parts of a flower. ","answer":"ANSWER: gynoecium (“jy-NEE-shee-um”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Rose hips are an “accessory” type of these structures because they are made up of tissue other than the ripened ovary. Other examples of these fleshy seed-bearing structures include apples and oranges. ","answer":"ANSWER: fruits "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Roses are classified into this clade because they have netted leaf veins, taproots, and tricolpate pollen grains. ","answer":"ANSWER: eudicots [or eudicotyledons or Eudicotidae] <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this Wallace Hartley–led group, whom Walter Lord argued played the hymn “Autumn” in his book A Night to Remember. A description is acceptable. ","answer":"ANSWER: the band aboard the Titanic [both underlined parts needed; accept synonyms for band like musicians or anything indicating the group performed music; prompt on band or musicians with “Where did they play?”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Hartley’s violin and other instruments were auctioned off in 2013 in this city, where the Titanic was built. Samson and Goliath are two massive cranes in this industrial city’s Queen’s Island harbor. ","answer":"ANSWER: Belfast [or Béal Feirste] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] During the 19th century, British shipbuilding boomed in Northern Ireland and this other constituent country, where the RMS Queen Elizabeth was built outside Glasgow. ","answer":"ANSWER: Scotland <CE/Geo/Other/Pop Culture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name these two countries that ruled as a single commonwealth until a series of 18th-century partitions. Their shared legislature, the sejm (“saym”), was strongly controlled by the szlachta (“SHLOCK-tuh”) noble class. ","answer":"ANSWER: Poland and Lithuania [or the Polish-Lithuanian Commonwealth; accept a combination of the Kingdom of Poland and the Grand Duchy of Lithuania] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Perhaps the greatest leader of the commonwealth was this man, who imitated Julius Caesar by saying, “I came, I saw, God conquered,” after defeating the Ottomans at the 1683 Battle of Vienna. ","answer":"ANSWER: John III Sobieski of Poland and Lithuania [or John Sobieski; accept Jan, Jonas, or Ioannes in place of “John,” but prompt on them without the number or identifier; prompt on John] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] The second and largest partition of the commonwealth was largely orchestrated by this longest-ruling female Russian tsar, who had earlier put down Pugachev’s Rebellion. ","answer":"ANSWER: Catherine the Great [or Catherine II; accept Yekaterina Alekseyevna or Yekaterina Velikaya; or Princess Sophie of Anhalt-Zerbst; prompt on Catherine or Yekaterina] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this language used by the nun Hrotsvitha of Gandersheim (“GAHN-durs-hime”). Medieval liturgical drama was written in this language, which was also used to write the Vulgate and most of Carmina Burana. ","answer":"ANSWER: Latin [accept Ecclesiastical Latin or Church Latin or Liturgical Latin or Medieval Latin or Vulgar Latin] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Hrotsvitha wrote plays in this broad genre. Hrotsvitha wrote in the style of Terence, who, like Plautus, was an ancient Roman playwright of this genre. ","answer":"ANSWER: comedy "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Two hundred years after Hrotsvitha, this medieval nun wrote Ordo Virtutum, the earliest surviving morality play. This composer and mystic described twenty-six visions of God in her manuscript Scivias. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hildegard von Bingen [or Saint Hildegard; or Hildegardis Bingensis; accept Sibyl of the Rhine] <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this quantity that is calculated by the formula one minus T-cold over T-hot for a Carnot (“kar-NO”) engine. ","answer":"ANSWER: efficiency "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This quantity is held constant in the adiabatic steps of the Carnot cycle. Processes are reversible if they conserve this quantity, the measure of disorder in a system. ","answer":"ANSWER: entropy [prompt on S] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This other thermodynamic cycle is often used by jet engines. It includes a combustion chamber and an expansion cylinder, where air and fuel are ignited. ","answer":"ANSWER: Brayton cycle <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this painting by William Holman Hunt that might have been intended as a companion to his work The Light of the World and depicts a woman rising from her lover’s lap. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Awakening Conscience "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Hunt was a member of this British artistic and literary movement, which sought to evoke medieval and early Renaissance art. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pre-Raphaelite Brotherhood [or PRB] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Hunt’s The Light of the World depicts this haloed figure knocking at a door. John Everett Millais (“mill-AY”) painted him in the House of His Parents, Mary and Joseph. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jesus Christ [accept either name] <Painting/Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name these things studied in the queer-influenced crip theory. Scholars differentiate impairments from these things, which are covered by the ADA and may include paraplegy and blindness. ","answer":"ANSWER: disabilities [accept disability studies; accept word forms like disabled] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This term encompasses such disabilities as chronic pain, dyslexia, and rheumatoid arthritis, which are not immediately noticeable to others. ","answer":"ANSWER: invisible disabilities [or hidden disabilities] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Disabled persons may be especially subject to this bias studied by Melvin Lerner, which is the belief that others tend to get the consequences they “deserve.” In a Linda Carli study on this “hypothesis,” respondents blamed the victim more when they heard a “bad” ending to the presented story. ","answer":"ANSWER: just world hypothesis [accept just world effect or just world phenomenon] <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this novel about Humphrey Van Weyden and the ruthless ship captain Larsen. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Sea-Wolf "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] The Sea-Wolf is by this American author, who wrote about the dog Buck in The Call of the Wild. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jack London [or John Griffith London; or John Griffith Chaney] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Wolf Larsen captains a ship named for this type of person. In a novella, a governess believes that Miss Jessel and Peter Quint are both people of this type. ","answer":"ANSWER: ghosts [or dead people; or spirits or other synonyms] (The novella is The Turn of the Screw.) <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this man who is often considered the first of the Valiant Sixty. Before marrying Margaret Fell, this man founded a tradition that witnessed a split between the Wilburite and the Gurneyite factions. ","answer":"ANSWER: George Fox "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Fox is considered the founder of this Protestant denomination. Pennsylvania was originally founded as a haven for this group, which is characterized by a belief in God’s presence in everyone, known as “inner light.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Quakers [or Religious Society of Friends] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Most Quakers don’t celebrate this observance, as they consider it to be hypocritical to fast for part of the year and live in excess for the rest. This observance lasts 40 days, beginning on Ash Wednesday. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lent [accept Quadragesima] <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this 19th-century conflict in which Argentina, Brazil, and another South American power allied to crush Paraguay, which lost over half its population. ","answer":"ANSWER: War of the Triple Alliance [prompt on Paraguayan War] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This nation was the third member of the Triple Alliance. Earlier, Paraguay tried to prevent Brazilian troops from forcing the Blanco party out of this country’s capital, Montevideo. ","answer":"ANSWER: Uruguay "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This president led Paraguay into the conflict. He died after making a last stand against Brazilian forces at Cerro Corá. ","answer":"ANSWER: Francisco Solano López <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this man whose “program” would allow all true statements to be derived mechanically from said axioms. ","answer":"ANSWER: David Hilbert [accept Hilbert’s program] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] The goals of Hilbert’s program are impossible to achieve, however, as proven by this mathematician in his incompleteness theorems. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kurt Friedrich Gödel (“GUR-tle”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] To prove his first incompleteness theorem, Gödel created a function that codes formal expressions with these numbers. The set of these numbers is denoted capital N. ","answer":"ANSWER: natural numbers [or the naturals] <Other Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Identify this professional from a thought experiment about abortion. Judith Jarvis Thomson argued that disconnecting yourself from an involuntary blood transfusion with this man would let him die but would not be murder. A description is fine. ","answer":"ANSWER: a master violinist [accept musician or clear equivalents describing a violin player or musical performer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] A chapter on abortion appears in the Canon of Medicine, which Avicenna wrote in this language. Aquinas often cited commentaries written in this language by Avicenna’s disciple Averroes. ","answer":"ANSWER: Arabic [or Al-‘Arabiyyah; or ʻarabī] (Aquinas hence called Averroes “the Commentator.”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Religious critiques of abortion may hinge on the process by which this thing enters the body. Aristotle’s De anima states that this immortal, immaterial essence of a person animates the body. ","answer":"ANSWER: the soul [or the spirit; or psyches; accept On the Soul or Peri Psyches] <Philosophy>"}]
